## Adam Gordon





#### **Full Stack Developer**

## **Professional Summary**

Full Stack Developer / Software Engineer with nearly 3 years of practical experience, with a growth mindset to consistently produce the absolute best of my ability. Looking for a position in which my unique attributes and perspective can thrive.

## **Work Experience**

# Freelance Full-Stack Software Developer Jan 2023–Present

Self

New York, USA

- Created numerous projects, both on my own and in a collaborative fashion, that feature Full Stack NextJS14 with TS/App Router.
- Developed a Stripe-powered fundraising site for Radical Flexibility, showcasing ability to integrate payment gateways and build functional e-commerce solutions.
- Completed 500+ hours of the Javascript Mastery Masterclass, resulting in extensive knowledge of SSR and modern web development practices.
- Gained hands-on experience with Laravel, OpenAl API, MongoDB, PostgresQL, TypeScript, Agile workflows, TailwindCSS, and Vue 3.0 through various personal and collaborative projects.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

**Diam International** 

**July 2022-December 2022** 

Hauppauge, NY

- Built a new authentication system allowing external customers to access business data, enhancing security and user
- Collaborated with other departments to process data and push it out to the customers quickly, increasing productivity for team members.
- Programmatically configure time tracking software, improving payroll process efficiency.
- Independently maintained the company database and server, ensuring continuous and reliable service.

## Project Manager/ Web Design Lead Intern January 2022-January 2023

**Cowan Consulting LLC** 

Brooklyn, NY (remote)

- Refactored an incomplete project into a React Application, enhancing code quality and project viability.
- Trained and supervised 8-10 interns, fostering a collaborative learning environment and ensuring successful project handover.
- Took initiative to ensure new team members were adequately trained, improving overall project execution and continuity.

#### **Education and Certifications**

JSM Masterclass Experience

2024

JSM NextJS Pro Course

2023

• B.Sc. Computer Science

SUNY Farmingdale, 3.81 Major GPA, 3.31 cumulative

2019-2022

Full Stack Developer Dev Today April 2024-June 2024

- Collaborated with a team to create a comprehensive social media website using NextJS, Prisma ORM, Supabase, Clerk for authentication, Tailwind, and ShadCN for styling, demonstrating teamwork and full-stack development capabilities.
- Implemented server-side rendering, query strings, and dynamic content filtering using Framer Motion for animations, improving technical proficiency in modern web development frameworks.
- React Hook Form for complex forms and validations, performing server actions whenever possible to take advantage of NextJS's capabilities. Developed UI friendly forms with a Rich Text Editor(TinyMCE) and Prism.js
- Designed onboarding and auth systems, comprehensive UI, and in-browser audio player, showcasing versatility in front-end and back-end development.

Full Stack Developer GitNote 2024

- Developed a knowledge repository for computer science education and career growth, using NextJS, MongoDB,
   NextAuth v4, Shadcn-UI for a component library, react-hook-form for form submission and validation, with SSR and query strings for specific searches.
- Worked solo from a Figma design with guidance from a senior developer to review code.
- Improved SEO support and page loading times with Next.js 13's server-side rendering, showcasing performance optimization skills.
- Worked independently from a Figma design with senior developer guidance for code reviews, demonstrating ability to take initiative and seek feedback.

Full Stack Developer <u>Dev OverFlow</u> 2023

- Developed a Stack Overflow like site that utilized MongoDB, OpenAl's API, and Tiny MCE to be able to read code syntax inside posts.
- Allows developers to communicate and collaborate to solve problems, as well as take advantage of new AI technologies to assist in coming to the correct answer, demonstrating adaptability and ability to integrate new technologies.
- Clerk Auth, MongoDB, NextJS w/ Tailwind as primary stack.

## **Technologies**, Languages, Soft Skills/Attributes

- NextJS, NuxtJS, Laravel, HTML, Css/Tailwind, React, Framer Motion, Vue 2 and 3.0, TypeScript, Javascript, Android apps. C# and Java experience as well.
- Have worked with SQL and NoSQL databases both extensively.
- External tools: Github Workflows, hosting a site on a blank VPS. Docker, Linux, Figma, Asana, Trello, Agile Development
- Integrating and building APIs Audio/video Web API's, Google, RapidAPI, OpenAI, etc.
- Previous stint doing sales and customer service, I have a growth mindset, a foundation of empathy with a focus on strong communication between team members.
- Proficient with multiple design patterns, most recently MVC (via Laravel) and NextJS14+ with the App router and React Server Components, RESTful patterns, GraphQL, DTOs, etc.

#### **Awards Honors and Certifications**

- JSM Masterclass
- NextJS Pro Course Certification
- President's List and Dean's List